Live from Atlantis The Palm,
in the presence of some of the biggest
and brightest stars in world football.
Welcome to Dubai.
Distinguished guests,
ladies and gentlemen, football fans,
good evening and welcome one and all.
Whether you're here in the room or
of course, tuning in from across the globe
to this, the 18th annual
Dubai International Sports conference,
as well as the 14th edition of the Dubai
Globe Soccer Award straight afterwards.
This one's organized annually
by the Dubai Sports Council.
Been doing this since 2006.
The Dubai International Sports Conference,
which is a member of the
Mohammed Bin Rashid Al Maktoum Global initiatives,
has delivered many,
many substantial debates driven
by the biggest names in the game.
They come to engage in discussions around
topics, topics which explore various
aspects that make football
the global phenomenon that it is.
So why are we here tonight?
Well, the theme of our discussion this
evening centers around sustainability and,
of course, performance in football.
While on the topic of sustainability,
we here at the Dubai Sports Council
and the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards
recognize the extraordinary importance
of environmental responsibility.
And we are committed to measuring
the emissions associated with this event.
Recognizing that responsibility,
we are committed to offsetting all
the measured emissions and of course,
taking further steps to eventually ensure
a carbon neutral event in the future.
So, without further ado,
it is time to get things started.
We're ready.
You're ready.
And facilitating this year's conference,
it is, of course, sports anchor from our
media father, CNN,
please welcome Amanda Davies.
Thank you very much indeed, Tom.
Welcome, everybody.
They say the hardest thing when you reach
the top is to stay at the top, don't they?
Perhaps a clichê, but it is true.
And there are not many in football
who have done it as consistently for such
a period of time as the gentlemen there,
who'll join us to share some of the secrets
of their success over
the next 30 minutes or so.
We are talking reaching peak performance
and sustaining it,
sustaining the beautiful game.
So let's crack on.
Please welcome two players integral
to last season's history making
campaign by Manchester City.
Firstly, a portuguese international
with 53 caps for his country,
consistently named in the FIFPro World XI
for his role in City's back line.
So integral to that european treble
winning season, it is Ruben Dias.
Welcome.
Next up, a player who joins him
in that back line, a fullback who's helped
City to five Premier League
titles since he joined in 2017.
As well as that incredible success last
year, known as one of the best fullbacks
of a generation, known for his pace,
strength and vision.
Ladies and gentlemen, Kyle Walker.
So that leaves us with one chair
and joining the Manchester City duo
a player in his 22nd season as
a professional footballer who spent
most of those as part of the GOATs.
The Greatest Of All Time
debate.
A five time Champions League winner,
the top goal scorer of all time
and showing no sign of slowing down,
having topped the world goal
scoring charts last year.
Please welcome Cristiano Ronaldo.
Amazing.
Thank you so much
for your time, gentlemen.
I mean, Cristiano, you've made no secret
of your Manchester United allegiance,
meaning you'd have a bit of a problem,
perhaps, moving to City,
but are you at least able to
appreciate the success and what they've
done in the last twelve months?
It was amazing.
First of all, good evening
or good night for everybody.
I'm so pleased to be here.
Thank you for the welcome.
Well, about them.
Amazing season.
Congratulations to Manchester City
for them and all players.
The coach, they did amazing work
and finally they win the Champions League.
In my opinion, they should deserve to win,
maybe two years ago,
but the timing always come and to be
honest, I enjoy to watch them to play.
I think they have a very good team, very
good coach, the system, how they play.
So amazing.
Congratulations.
Yeah.
And that doesn't come easily, I guess.
From you, nothing is easy.
They deserve.
Ruben, so much had been made about
the weight and so close,
yet so far for you in the City team.
What psychologically did it
mean to get over that line?
Well, I think until you actually do it,
you've not done it.
But also I think that,
especially when we're talking about a club
that has done it for the first time,
it takes a process to do that.
So, in the end, today,
you see these faces collecting the big
award, but it's been a work of many years.
And in the end, it's not just us,
it's a whole process.
And the congratulations,
it's obviously for us, but for all
the guys that participated before,
managers, players, everyone involved,
because to bring the club to where it was,
to where it is now,
I think that's the biggest
prize we all have.
Kyle, what is the secret of the success?
I mean, this is the point in the season
where you're looking from the outside,
people waiting for the leaders to have
a wobble, to make a few mistakes.
This is where City
cranks through the gears.
Yeah.
I mean, in recent years,
we've known to kick on after the Christmas
period,
but I think what the key and the secret
is wanting to do it again and again.
I think the manager is
a massive driving force in that.
But I think also some of the players
that we've brought in took out.
We've always made sure that we've kept
the high standards and made sure
that we keep winning year after year.
And Pep very openly said, this is
not just about one Champions League crown.
You've got to go on and win it again.
Cristiano, that is something
that you did with Real Madrid.
Not just once, but twice, but three times.
What was the key in that, do you think?
The key.
Well, it's difficult to say.
I think it's belief, the dedication,
hard work, and in my opinion,
nothing is a coincidence.
So I think they have potential
to do it the same.
I hope no, but they have potential.
But I think they have potential
because they still have good team.
Some players,
they are on prime,
they play good football.
I think they have a good chance
to win the Champions League again.
But we will see many factors will happen.
Who do you see as
the favorites this season?
The favorite?
Yeah,
well, they're always in the top to be
the favorites, but they're
always the same clubs.
Bayern, Manchester City, Real Madrid.
I don't know.
I think that three will be
the finals, I think.
Who do you see as the favorites, Kyle?
Yeah, I think just there you look at them,
three teams, Bayern Munich,
Real Madrid, Manchester City.
We're all there with good players.
You know, who've a chance
of winning it, you'd say.
But I also feel that you need luck.
You need a little bit of luck
in the Champions League to make sure
that you get to the final and then it's
down for big players and big moments
to then also go and win you that game,
which we've got a lot
in the dressing room.
Obviously, I'm sat next to him
and he's a fantastic player.
One of the best that's
ever graced the game.
But I think what's very key with our
team is that there's no standout.
We're all a collective and we're a team,
and we rely on each other to make
sure that we can get over the line.
We look at the other night and Kevin's
come on on the 70th minute and obviously
the capabilities that Kevin has and stuff
like that, but it's a process, it's a team
game and that's what we're in it for.
And we make sure that we
get to places where we can, for a collective.
Cristiano,
it's a team game, without doubt.
But there was all eyes on you as one
player when you made the move to Saudi.
I think it's fair to say there were a few
people who weren't
the most positive about it.
But how did that act
for you as a motivation?
Well, I thought will be a good move to me.
Why not
to give a chance to another countries
with my football,
with my passion, to change mentalities?
Why not?
And I'm capable to do that.
I'm not be arrogant,
but I said that one year ago.
The things change, the world change,
the football change,
the rules change, everything change.
So my move, I think it was a good move.
I feel so happy.
Many players move there, coaches,
directors, even nutritionists,
they moving there.
So the Saudi is in the process.
That will take long.
But in a life we always say step
by step we reach to the highest level.
So I believe they're going to be
in the top three-four in the world.
But step by step I think
we're going to reach that.
Where do you think the level is now?
You're a year on, aren't you?
You're a year on to your
life in Saudi Arabia.
Where do you think the level is now?
The level right now?
To be honest, I think the Saudi League is
not worse than France's
league to be in my opinion.
And French league I think you have two,
three teams with a good level.
In Saudi now,
I think it's more competitive.
They can say whatever they want.
It's just my opinion and I played there one
year so I know what I'm talking about.
But I think right now we are better
than France League, so we still improve.
What do you think is the key in terms
of taking it to the next level?
The key, you have many factors that apply
to improve the league.
As I say before,
they have many things to improve.
But I think with the powerful people
behind to help to change a little bit
the culture of football, the bad habits,
I think we're going to reach in one point
that the people there
in Saudi will be proud.
The investment there, it's huge.
So why not believe on that?
Like in Saudi, even in Dubai,
the things change and the world
change so they deserve opportunities.
How much did you use
the criticism as motivation?
Say again?
How much did you use
the criticism as motivation?
It's part of the journey.
I'm always dealing with that.
I'm professional 22 years.
It's part of my journey to be a better
man, a better player, a better father.
So it's good.
I like when the people doubt about me
and I prove again that
one year with successful I had last
year a little bit difficult journey.
But I'm glad that things happened because
make me feel more strong and you can
see this year I did a fantastic season.
I was the best goal scorer, imagine,
to beat that animals, the young lions,
like Haaland, for example, with the goals.
So I'm proud.
I'm 39 soon and I'm still
looking good, so I'm proud.
Ruben, you've had the pleasure,
I'm guessing, of being a teammate
of both Cristiano and Erling.
Which would you rather on your team?
Difficult question.
Well, in the end, they're
just different players.
Obviously, Cristiano is older now,
he's in a different stage of his career.
But obviously,
when it comes to choose between players,
I always stay away from that question,
just because everyone's different and you
have many different ways of seeing
the game these days,
and one might fit best one kind of idea,
the other one might fit best
the other one.
But in the end, I think I wouldn't be
badly served with either of them because
the one thing they both
do a lot is scoring goals.
Cristiano was talking about using
criticism and the skeptics as motivation.
Thierry Henry recently revealed that he
now looks back and thinks he was suffering
with mental depression and low
points during his career.
How do you deal with the tough moments
yet still perform on the pitch?
Well, I think, since young, we're told,
and we grow up knowing that that's
unfortunately part of being a footballer,
especially on the top level.
The more visibility you have,
the more open you are to criticism,
as much as you are also open to when
things go well, to get cheered
and beloved by everyone.
It's about, I think,
building that strong mindset that will
shield you in a way and protect yourself
when the times get a bit more tough.
And then in the end,
it's about a little bit of fight
with yourself and always coming up on top.
A bit like you were saying,
all of us get criticism in a moment of our
lives for personal matters,
for professional reasons.
It can be from whatever side
you might sometimes not expect.
But what does matter is that
you always stay strong and you always
remember where you're going for.
And I think in here, in this room,
we have many examples of that.
How much do you rely
on yourself in those moments?
How much do you lean on the team?
I do think that,
especially on those moments of criticism,
is when you most rely on yourself,
is when you most have to rely on
everything you've built yourself with.
Because that's the moment where probably
you're not going to have so much people
around you trying to help
you and supporting you.
And that's the one moment in which you
just grind it out and you show the world
and everyone around you that you're there.
And people can talk,
people can say whatever they want to say,
but you are who you want to be.
Let's talk about Pep.
What is life under Pep Guardiola like?
It's tough on days.
I think I speak for probably everyone now
that for what he's achieved,
what he does in football,
what he teaches you, not just
as a football player,
but as a person.
No pressure, I mean, look at that glare.
No, but he's fantastic
and he probably knows that.
But it is tough because he
demands so much from you.
But it's also what you should do every day
and come to training and make sure
that you give 100% and you should
demand from yourself as well.
But sometimes you do have off days,
but you can't have off days with him
because as soon as you have off days,
he's normally shouting at you.
Ederson said, the thing with Pep is
that he's always ten steps ahead
of everybody else.
As a player,
how hard is that to keep up with?
Well, I think
it shouldn't be difficult,
because if there's one thing besides
having the manager we have
and the structure we have,
is that we also have players that want
to be forward as well,
even though sometimes we're not,
and he's the one that keeps on pulling us.
But as a player,
if you're ambitious and if you want
to keep on winning,
especially after so many great things
that this team has done, this is the kind
of person you need next to you.
Obviously, it's an effort of everyone,
not just him, not just us, everyone.
But he's the man in front of the ship,
so it is crucial that he's
got that mentality.
How do you compare, Cristiano, what you
see from Pep with Sir Alex Ferguson?
I think the mindset of the winners,
they are different, in my opinion.
Personality, the character,
the way they see the life,
the way they see the players,
the way they see the difficult moments.
The top players and top coaches,
they're thinking different.
As I say before, no coincidence
that he win what he won.
So no miracles, hard work.
You see different things that the other
ones, like Sir Alex Ferguson,
and of course other coaches,
too, they are different.
And when you look at what happens next
in your career,
what happens next in your career,
how much longer can you
keep this level going?
I don't know.
I live day by day.
How much do you rely on the data and the
facts and how much of it is instinct?
Listen,
with some issues that I had,
personal and professional make me feel
and make me thinking in a different way.
As I told you before,
I thinking the present and the moment.
The moment is good.
I feel good.
I still capable to do
some goals, to help my team,
to help the national team too.
So I will carry on.
The moment when I finish?
I don't know, to be honest.
But of course will be soon.
Soon, I mean, ten years more.
But I'm joking.
So relative.
It's all relative.
I don't know.
Let's see.
Are you instinct or data?
Instinct.
I feel for me it's more
on just play on how you feel.
I think when you're happy and when you're
feeling happy in yourself,
we're doing the job that everyone loves.
Everyone as a small kid playing football.
We wanted to do what we're doing now.
So I just want to enjoy it.
I want to enjoy it to the fullest capacity
and then just play
with a smile on my face.
I think for Cristiano, whenever he
wants to retire, he will retire.
He deserves the right of that.
But I'm more off instinct and just
doing what makes me happy.
As the calendar gets longer,
Bernardo Silva was very open,
talking about the Club World
Cup and the expansion of that.
How easy is that?
How much tougher does it make your
job to keep the level where you are?
I don't think it becomes tougher
because we're doing what we love.
Like I just said before, this is what
we're paid to do and we're
paid well to do it.
So to achieve what we've achieved,
I feel we probably should have won
a Champions League before when we
got to the final against Chelsea.
But you do need setbacks in life.
You do need things to come back from,
or nearly moments to then also achieve
your dream, which we went unachieved
to then win the Super cup and the
Club World cup after that was a bonus.
You're in them competitions because
you won the Champions League.
So listen, we're in the FA cup,
obviously still fighting very hard
for the Premier League and still
in the Champions League.
So we'll try and replicate
what we did last year.
Who knows what's going
to happen, but why not?
How is your career compared to what you
had hoped for when you were
starting out as a young boy?
Well, to start at Sheffield United
and then go to Tottenham at the age of 19
and leave there at 27 with no medals was
tough.
To come here and won the amount
of Premier Leagues that I've
won in a short amount of time.
And obviously the Champions League,
it's been more than ever dreamed of.
But that's not just me that's without
the past and present
players that have been here.
It's just been a journey,
and it's been a journey that I've loved,
and that's why I've extended my contract,
obviously, at Manchester City, and it's
a team that's fully in my heart.
How much of your career,
and I'll ask this to Ruben
as well, how much of your career was
dependent on your academy career and life
as a schoolboy, and how much has it
been your development subsequently?
I think it teaches you
certain things or certain paths
in your life when you are a schoolboy.
I think probably now you look at Rico
and Oscar that are here tonight,
that I think the born old Phil,
who was born in 2000,
that their paths are going to be
completely different to what mine was.
But I think everyone has their journey.
Everyone has their journey in life,
and it's brought us to where we all are
today, enjoying this moment
and this special night.
And I just feel what your path is.
It's destiny.
Ruben, in terms of how much was set when
you were at the academies in Portugal?
Well, obviously, I guess I consider myself
very fortunate to have been
brought up in Benfica's academy.
I don't know if people are very aware,
but the academy has probably everything
a young player can need to become
whatever you want to become.
But I think you can come
from different backgrounds.
At home, I had a different example,
a very different one, my own brother,
and he was living in another
way of making his own way.
But I think just being around football
in a way, in a dressing room, dealing with
other young footballers,
it just helps you develop.
It helps you.
I've met many people from different
backgrounds that just
get a very good shape in terms of just
getting away from their normal place
and getting into football in which you
just deal with different communities
and different kinds of people.
So in the end, yeah,
I think the final result,
whether you make it to the top or not,
is always going to be something
better than what you were before.
Kyle mentioned Rico coming through.
What do you see as you guys see as your
role in terms of developing the next
generation and allowing them to flourish
not only in the dressing room,
but on the pitch as well?
He's actually not that old.
He just talks like he's 33.
He's one a lot.
No, we try and make sure
that it's enjoyable.
You want to come to work and enjoy it.
First and foremost, me, Kevin,
Ruben, Rodri, Bernardo, the captains.
We make sure that it's an enjoyable place.
You come here because you're happy,
but we're here to win,
and that's the main thing.
And like Ruben said, it comes
from the driving force as the manager.
But our job as the captains is
to make sure that the lads are happy.
The lads are fully focused on what we need
to do and where this team is shaped from,
is that we're his voice in the changing room.
And I don't know whether you
saw this week Vinicius Jr.
scoring his goal
and paying tribute to you.
How much pride do you take from that in
terms of inspiring the next generation?
It's good when you have a family,
big family, like I am.
So it's good to be proud of your kids.
Junior do it his way.
I think he have a good talent still,
to improve more, I need to teach him some
tricks, but I think he's in a good way.
He's a good boy.
He like to play football.
He have the drive.
So he make me happy.
What is your key bit of advice to the next
generation, in terms of making
it to the top and staying there?
Believe.
I think you should believe in everything.
And, of course, the rest.
It's the dedication, the hard work.
Listen to people who know more than you,
who they have more experience than you,
and believe in your talent.
I think it's the main point.
And what a note to end on.
Everybody nodding.
Thank you ever so much,
gentlemen, for your time.
It's been a real pleasure to speak to you.
Some fantastic insight from some of the
best, most successful of their generation.
Plenty more silverware on the cards later
this season, of course,
and perhaps even later this evening.
Ladies and gentlemen, Cristiano Ronaldo,
Ruben Diaz and Kyle Walker.
The event is tonight.
You can't be late.
I will be there.
I'm sending you support.
We've been expecting you.
So, a few clues for you.
A central defensive midfielder
who is as tough as they come.
A player celebrated for his
ball winning ability.
Ranger passing and goal scoring.
Someone who relishes the big occasion.
And has shone both the club
and international level.
One more clue.
He's represented his country 75 times.
A player synonymous with silverware
and one of the finest the world has seen,
bringing the ceremonial Globe Soccer
trophy to our breathtaking venue.
A copper America champion.
Have you got it yet?
Well, he's also a three time La Liga winner.
A five time UEFA Champions League winner
and a champion of the FIFA Club World
cup three times.
Ladies and gentlemen, expertly brought
in by Dubai police, the great Casemiro.
Quite the entry indeed.
And quite a difficult entry to follow.
But we will indeed.
Amanda, great to have you
back here for the awards.
Oh, we will try to follow.
We will try.
We welcome the world and literally
the world, tuning in from all corners
of the globe with open arms to this,
the United Arab Emirates,
under the leadership of
His Highness Sheik Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum,
the vice president and the prime minister
and the ruler of Dubai,
and under the guidance of
His Highness Sheik Hamdan bin Mohammed bin
Rashid Al Maktoum,
the crown prince of Dubai and the chairman
of Dubai's executive council.
A huge thank you to our illustrious
partners, sponsors and stakeholders
who work tirelessly to make
the Nakheel Dubai Globe Soccer awards,
the spectacle that it is today.
From our strategic partner,
the Dubai Sports Council,
and supporting partners, Esaad,
our platinum sponsors, Audi Al Nabooda Automobiles,
Emirates, Serie A,
Power Horse and Koora Break.
To our gold sponsors, Silversands, Italpreziosi,
Atlantis, Tatatu, Sushisamba,
Montegrappa, XDubai and Majesty Yachts.
Not forgetting our Media Partners,
our event host broadcaster MBC, CNN, Marca,
SSC, LaPresse, Sky, SportBusiness
and of course, IMAGO.
Excitment, as you can imagine,
has been building up in our voting process.
We tallied 70 million votes coming from across
over 200 territories heading into tonight's ceremony.
Well, in an evening where we applaud
excellence, stars from around the world
are with us at the spectacular
Atlantis The Palm.
From all time greats to rising stars, all
have made their way to our iconic city.
We have with us, Manchester City
and their squad of Champions, the one and only...
Tom...
We've got a little technical problem,
so I'm going to pick up here.
Sorry.
We have with us Manchester City and their
squad of champions, the one
and only Cristiano Ronaldo.
Former England and Chelsea
captain, John Terry.
The legend that is Fabio Capello.
The Manchester United duo
of Harry Maguire and Casemiro.
Super agents Jorge Mendes,
Ali Barat and Frank Trimboli,
and of course, the World cup
winning coach Lionel Scaloni.
2023 was a magical footballing year as
footballers around the world left
an enduring mark on the beautiful game.
Yeah.
After a year which provided an array
of magical moments,
we come together tonight to honor,
well, you, the very, very best.
We are live and interactive on all social
media platforms,
so don't forget
to use the hashtag #globesoccer.
Listen, before we go any further,
I'm sure each and every one of you in this
room will know that it has been a sad few
months across the football world as we
have lost three iconic figures recently.
Tonight,
we here at the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards
would like to come together to pay
tributes to three legendary World Cup winners.
In October last year,
former England and Manchester United icon
Sir Bobby Charlton passed away
86, while at the beginning of January,
just a few weeks ago,
we lost brazilian Mario Zagallo,
the first man, of course, to win the
FIFA World cup as both player and coach.
And then just days ago,
we lost another -
German Great Franz Beckenbauer, the second man to have
won the World Cup as a player and coach.
He passed away at the age of 78.
Three men, three greats
who left a lasting legacy.
Rest in peace, Sir Bobby Charlton,
Mario Zagallo and Franz Beckenbauer.
So, on with the show.
Yeah.
Without further ado,
let's get the ball rolling.
So let's kick off the awards, if we may.
The first award is one that recognizes
the efforts of the stars on the rise,
players whose potential knows no bounds,
and the player who's destined to reach
the very summit of the football world.
This year, no different,
as our list of nominees for the
Power Horse Emerging Player of the Year features
the finest young stars who, in fact,
they've already left their
mark on the beautiful game.
Your finalists for the
Power Horse Emerging Player are...
So we're on to the first winner of the evening.
This is the Power Horse Emerging Player at this,
the 14th Dubai Globe Soccer Awards.
And the winner is
England, Real Madrid,
midfielder - Jude Bellingham.
Well, sadly, Jude Bellingham can't
be here with us this evening.
He's in camp with Real Madrid.
But the latest recipient of the Power Horse Emerging Player
award sent us this video.
Hi, everyone.
I just want to thank Globe Soccer,
Dubai Sports Council and of course
the fans for voting me
for this brilliant award.
Sorry I couldn't attend in person,
but I'm very grateful to receive it.
Thank you all.
Thank you, Jude, and congratulations.
Now, also last year there was the crowning
of new world champions,
the consolidation of greatness
and the rise of emerging forces.
Amongst the glory,
there emerged superstars aplenty.
Looking at individual performances,
team contributions and efforts across both
domestic clubs and national teams,
we answer the question now of just who is
the Best Women's Footballer in the world?
Indeed.
So let's move on to your finalists
for the Nakheel Dubai Globe Soccer
Awards Best Women's Player.
And the finalists are...
All very deserving winners.
But there is one who has without doubt
dominated in the last twelve months.
This award has been sponsored
by Esaad and the winner is...
Aitana Bonmati from Spain and FC Barcelona.
So let's hear from the Best Women's Player
at the Dubai Globe Soccer awards.
Here is Aitana Bonmati.
Hello, I am Aitana Bonmati.
I would have liked to be here in Dubai with you, but as you know, I have an important commitment with the club.
We are playing the Super Cup in Madrid, so I wanted to send you a message of thanks for the award.
As I always like to say, these individual awards come after a great collective effort.
You also know that this year we were lucky enough to win the Champions League with Barça.
The World Cup with the national team
has been a unique and round year,
so I owe it all to my teammates, staff,
club workers, directors and the national team.
A big hug and I wish you all the best.
Well, it was only going to be a good
reason that Aitana couldn't be here.
She said she would have loved to have been
here in Dubai, but Barça have a game
against Madrid in the Super Cup.
She said she's grateful for the award,
but individual honors are
the result of teamwork, she said.
There's a bit of a team there
this evening, isn't there?
Aitana said she says she owes everything
to her teammates, staff, managers,
as well as everyone at the national team.
Yeah.
Congratulations to both of our first two
winners of the evening, and thanks
again to Aitana for those kind words.
We at the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards.
Well, we've got a bit of an announcement
for you, a little bit of a surprise.
As we mentioned, not our first rodeo,
done a few of these.
But the big news is
we here at the divine Globe Soccer Awards
are truly by name and by nature,
going global this year,
the football world is bracing itself
for the inaugural event of our
very first intercontinental series.
And the first stop,
any ideas?
Well, I'll give you one clue.
It's in Europe.
After more than ten years in Dubai,
the Globe Soccer awards head
to the stunning Costas Smeralda region
in Sardinia for the first stop
of the intercontinental series.
The inaugural european edition will be
held at the iconic Cala di Volpe Hotel
in May 2024,
where the best european football talent
will be rewarded for their
outstanding achievements.
Sardinia, the end of May.
Sounds like a good idea.
I'm in.
Do join us there.
Right on with the awards.
We'd now like to welcome onto stage
His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum,
the Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council,
accompanied by
His Excellency Mattar al Tayer,
Vice Chairman of the Dubai Sports
Council, to present the awards.
Welcome.
Thank you for your hospitality.
Now, it has been a year where football
in the Middle East has really
captured the imagination.
Domestic and regional brilliance has seen
plenty of focus fixed
firmly on the region.
And with several big name arrivals you
might just have heard about,
clubs from across the Middle East
have really embraced the spotlight.
Consistency and ultimately excellence was
essential in us honoring
the Best Club in the Middle East.
Yeah, this one's generously
sponsored by our friends at Tatatu.
Let's have a look at the finalists then,
for you in this category.
And the finalists are...
And your Nakheel Dubai
Globe Soccer award for Best Middle East Club goes to
Egyptian Giants Al Ahly.
Now, collecting the award fo Best Middle East Club of the Year
is the president of Al Ahly.
Please welcome to the stage
Mahmoud el Khatib.
I understand you want to say a few words.
All yours.
Mahmoud el Khatib,
congratulations.
Thank you very much.
Yes, indeed.
Congratulations to Al Ahly
and all the team there now.
Right, from facilitating transfers
to negotiating contracts,
securing sponsorship
and of course endorsement deals.
As you well know, the work of an agent is
extremely rewarding,
but also incredibly taxing.
Or so they say.
These are the individuals
who look after every aspect
of a footballer's career.
And that allows the players
to do what they need to do.
Focus on the job at hand, on the pitch.
Yeah.
Now, over the last twelve months,
we've seen deals which have further
emphasized just how crucial
the role the agent plays.
And we are here tonight to pay
tribute to those often unsung heroes.
Your nominees are...
So this one is brought to you by X Dubai.
Time now for us to unveil to you
the 2023 Dubai Globe Soccer Award
Best Agent.
And the award goes to...
Jorge Mendes.
Jorge Mendes and his Gestifute Agency
boast only the finest talents in the world.
The likes of Enzo Fernandez
and Gonçalo Ramos.
Congratulations.
I understand you want to say a few words.
Good evening.
It's an honor to be here again.
Thank you very much to Globe
Soccer for the award.
I'm deeply proud.
Last year was one of the best
years ever of my company - Gestifute.
This year I'm going to try again
to improve as much as possible to do even better,
with hard work,
ambition and passion.
I would like to thanks to my wife,
to all my family, my Gestifute
team and managers and players.
Thank you very much and
Happy New Year for all of you.
Thank you.
Congratulations.
Okay.
From the agents, we now move to the master
strategist for the next award,
the individual ultimately responsible
for the football operations of any club.
It's now time for us to pay
tribute to the sporting directors.
Their duties may vary,
but ultimately the sporting director
develops and protects the overall vision
and philosophy as well as implementing
strategy required for sustainable
success at the club.
The link between
the boardroom and the pitch.
A large part of a club's success falls
on the sporting director.
Let's have a look at your
finalists in this category.
And they are...
Generously sponsored by Emirates,
your Nakheel Dubai Globe Soccer Awards
Best Sporting Director is Cristiano Guintoli.
Guintoli's crown and glory came at the end
of last season when Napoli won
the Scudetto for the very first time since
1990, only the third in their history.
This was due to his incredible talent
acquisition, transfer, maneuvering and
collaboration with coach Luciano Spaletti.
A move to Juventus followed.
Given his track record,
there is little doubt that success
will of course find the Bianconeri.
Cristiano, congratulations.
Please come and say a few words.
Come on.
Thank you.
I am honored to be here tonight.
And for me, 23 is very
important year, historical year.
And we won the scudetto with Napoli.
And I would like to thank
my president, Aurelio De Laurentiis,
my coach, Luciano Spaletti, all players and all
people that worked with me in the past.
Now, the last but not least is important.
I want to thank my family
and for me it's very, very important
because they help me to improve every day.
Now, I started with a new adventures
with Juventus and now our objective,
we want to go directly in Champions League
and it's possible to win the Cup Italia.
But in the future, I think it's important
to be here again
for another award for Juventus.
Thank you again.
Well done indeed
to Cristiano.
Well done to all the team.
Moving on to the next award.
Often the difference
between success and failure.
Not only does the modern day goalkeeper
have to be dominant in stopping opposition
attacks, but also well capable
of initiating offensive moves as well.
From sweeper, keeper, supreme stopper,
the ball playing minder.
There were some blinding performances
that left the football
world watching on in awe.
That's why we now pay tribute
to the Best Goalkeeper.
Brought to you by Sushisamba,
your finalists for Best Goalkeeper are...
Right then, the winner,
Best Goalkeeper for the 14th annual
Dubai Globe Soccer Awards is Ederson.
A shot stopper
of the highest quality!
Ederson played a heroic role
in Manchester City's all conquering team,
keeping 19 clean sheets in the process.
With his ball playing abilities setting
him apart, even claiming an assist
in the Premier League,
Ederson continues to perfect the role of
sweeper, keeper and traditional stopper.
The brazilian international has firmly
established himself as one
of the best in the world.
A quick photo first and then, of course,
we'll ask Ederson for a few words.
Amanda, over to you.
Congratulations.
I think it was a popular choice
in the room, we were talking earlier about
the fact that you said the key to this
City success is that Pep
is always ten steps ahead.
How tough is that for you as players?
For me, it's so easy to
work with Pep.
I work with Pep, for like six years a half.
I collected some trophies.
It's very important.
I think Pep is very intensive guy,
push the team open.
Push the players for me is no different.
Congratulations.
I suspect there might be a little bit more
silverware, goldware heading your
way in the not too distant future.
Ederson, the Best Goalkeeper of the Year.
Congratulations.
Yeah, congratulations to Ederson.
Yet another award for Manchester City.
Okay, from goalkeeper,
let's move our way up the field,
if we can the driving force,
the visionaries, they're quite simply,
well, the conductors of the orchestras.
We're talking midfielders here.
The link between defense and attack.
The midfielder needs to always be one step
ahead and often the success of a midfielder
often determines the success
of the team as a whole.
Yeah.
As football continues to evolve,
so does the role of the midfielder
and in 2023 there were some
serious players who raised the bar.
Your finalists then for the
Nakheel Dubai Globe Soccer Award,
Best Midfielder are...
The award's been generously sponsored
by Power Horse and
the Best Midfielder goes to...
Manchester City's Rodri
Rodri is a player who lives for the big moments.
The spaniard cemented himself as one
of the finest central defensive
midfielders in the world thanks to his
unwavering consistency and reliability
at the heart of midfield,
with his superb shooting ability
and innate elegance,
Rodri was ever present throughout City's
historic season.
When it mattered the most,
he was also a match winner as he scored
the goal which secured City a first
ever Champions League crown.
Congratulations again to Rodri
and let's hear from him now.
Just a quick word if I may.
There were so many important moments,
particularly from you last season.
Perhaps none more so than that goal
in the Champions League
final in Istanbul, though.
At what point did you allow yourself
to believe it was the winning goal?
Well, I mean, to be fair,
I think it was like 20 minutes left.
I didn't thought it was done,
but the gap was open.
Of course we were close to it,
but I remember that moment when we all
come each other and hug each other.
I was saying, guys, we have
the 20 minutes of your lives.
Let's keep pushing.
And you can see in the chances that Eddie
saves in the line and Ruben flicked to
the corner like the game wasn't finished.
But when they whistle, I mean,
all the motions come into all these years
that we work in the project
at the end came succeed.
And I cannot be more proud
of myself and my teammates.
I think was unbelievable season for us.
How many times have you watched it back?
I say before, I think it's of course,
so far the most important
moment of my career.
Maybe 5000 times,
but always it's not enough.
So, yeah, very proud of what I did.
My family, everyone
surrounding me is so proud.
So I can only dream about doing it again.
Yeah, I haven't got the math quick enough
to work out how many times that is a day.
We're only, what, six months on.
But congratulations, I've no doubt there's
many more really special moments to come.
Thank you ever so much and well done.
Please go and rejoin your teammates.
Congratulations indeed.
Okay, let's move to the women's game.
Women's club football continues to reach
new frontiers with every passing season.
2023, the standard was raised yet again.
More investment gave more success,
which led to clubs across the world
reaching unparalleled heights.
We had league honors,
cup success, continental glory.
We are here tonight in Dubai
to pay tribute to the very best.
Kindly sponsored by Koora Break,
your finalists
for the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards
Best Women's Club are...
The Best Women's Club at the
Dubai Globe Soccer Awards is FC Barcelona.
It's been another dominant
year for FC Barcelona.
They landed their 8th Liga F title
at a canter, winning 28 of 30 games,
scoring 118 goals
and conceding just ten times.
This was their fourth title in a row.
Having exemplified their domestic
dominance, they have a score
to settle in the Champions League.
Recovering from a two goal deficit against
Wolfsburg in the final,
they showed their determination.
The 3-2 victory ensured the trophy
headed back to Catalonia
for a second time in three seasons.
Accepting the award is Xavier Puig,
the Director responsible for
Women’s Football at FC Barcelona.
Congratulations.
Please, the mic is yours.
Good evening everyone.
It is a pleasure for me to represent
FC Barcelona in the occasion of receiving
the Best Women's Team of the Year
award at the Globe Soccer Awards.
This award, the result of many people
work and the club commitment
to women's football.
On behalf of your player, Aitana Bonmati,
I also want to thank Globe Soccer
Awards for the Best Player award.
Aitana is currently in Madrid focusing
on the Super Cup final that they'll play
tomorrow and we hope will be
our first trophy this season.
Thank you again for these awards.
We are immensely grateful.
Thank you very much.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Congratulations to all
the team at FC Barcelona.
All right, I think we should take
a moment now to honor a couple of careers.
It's a nice tradition
of the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards when we
get the opportunity to say thank you
to some of the greats of the game.
The Career Award serves as recognition
to those who have scaled the very
highest peaks of the footballing world.
Players out there who've captured
the imagination and who provided moments
of sheer genius on the field of play.
Our first Career Award has been generously
sponsored by Serie A and it goes to former
England and Chelsea captain John Terry.
Cheers, JT.
Well done.
Cheers.
Congratulations to John.
Let's see if we can get a few words.
Come on over.
Good evening, everyone.
It's a huge honor for me
to win this award tonight.
I'd like to thank Dubai Sports Council
and Globe Soccer Awards
for hosting us all this evening.
Individual awards are fantastic to win
but impossible to do without
teammates and managers.
I've been very fortunate to play with some
great managers and some of the best
players across the world as well.
I'd like to dedicate this award this
evening to a man that gave
me my debut a long time ago,
Gianluca Vialli, who sadly
lost his life last year.
Luca was a manager that believed in me
and gave me my first opportunity
at Chelsea and I'm very thankful for that.
So, Luca, this one's for you.
I love you and thank you.
Just before you go,
if there was one thing that Luca Vialli
taught you, told you that you
carry with you, what would it be?
He said to me, I'll never forget it.
He said to me in the showers,
don't do what I do, do what I say,
and that stays with me.
I'm just checking,
have you got your kids under there?
I have, actually.
And listen, Chelsea, at the moment
it's not been the best run for them.
There was a call this week that perhaps
you should get in that dressing room.
If you were in that dressing room,
what would your message be?
You know what, I think
we're seeing cycles.
I think when I look back 10-15 years ago,
Man United were dominating
the Premier League.
Chelsea came along,
we dominated for a little bit and now
Pep and Man City are dominating.
And I've said it for a little bit now.
It's going to be hard to catch them.
They're the best team,
they've got some great individual players
and the way they do it year
after year is incredible.
I managed to win the Premier League twice
on the bounce and it's
very difficult to do so.
I wish them well.
They're a fantastic team.
But unfortunately, Chelsea are
a little bit off it at the moment.
But given time, the manager needs time.
Pochettino is a great manager.
I've seen him work on a daily basis.
We're a young squad of players as well,
but we're a long way off of the likes
of Man City and Liverpool at the moment.
Congratulations.
Enjoy this moment.
Thank you.
Well done.
Thank you, everyone.
Congratulations to John.
Well deserved.
Right, enjoy now, as we get into the next
of our awards, time now to pay tribute
to yet another star who's secured his
place in the history books of the game.
This award is brought
to you by Silversands.
Ladies and gentlemen,
our next Career Award winner is none other than
World Cup winning
coach Lionel Scaloni.
Lionel Scaloni was the architect of one
of football's most fascinating stories.
Taking over a struggling Argentina team in
2018, he helped them find a new identity.
Los Albiceleste flourished.
Success of the Cup America
in 2021 ended a 28 year drought.
But the best was yet to come.
With Leo Messi at the forefront,
Argentina felt as if they had
a date with destiny in Qatar.
After a final for the ages,
Argentina were world champions
for a third time in their history.
Scaloni has catapulted into greatness.
So many congratulations.
The mic is yours.
Hello.
Sorry for my English.
It's very bad.
I speak Spanish.
Thank you very much for the award.
I dedicate it to my country, to my people.
Sincerely, it has been a movie,
a film, what we have achieved.
I dedicate it to them, to all Argentines,
to my technical staff,
to Pablo Aimar, to Walter Samuel, Roberto Ayala,
Matías Manna, Martin Tocalli, Luis Martín, Rodrigo Barrios
all of them who have helped me to get this incredible award.
To my family, who is here today,
my wife and my children, I love you.
Thank you very much.
That's all I have to say. Thank you.
So many congratulations.
I don't think we got the answer
to whether or not you've persuaded
Leo Messi to stick around for 2026 or not.
Tom.
We move on,
then to the next of our awards.
Thank you very much
indeed for your patience.
All those tuning in around the world,
all of us with us here in Dubai
tonight on this evening of winners.
Next up, the quest to be recognized as,
quite simply,
the finest club in the world.
It's never ending.
Find the perfect balance, both on and off
the pitch is where the good
gets separated from the great.
In 2023, bar was raised.
And in an era when football has been
at this most competitive,
there were clubs out there who flourished,
which allowed them to excel yet further.
Your nominees for the
Best Men's Club are...
For the Best Men's Club,
this year's Nakheel Dubai Globe
Soccer awards are...
Time for something
a little bit special, I think.
The team who won
the Premier League for a 7th time
and 5th in the last six seasons.
The club who also lifted the FA Cup
for the 7th time in their history.
The undefeated winners
of the UEFA Champions League.
Which, of course,
allowed them to go on to win the
UEFA Super cup for the very first time.
And the team who landed the FIFA Club
World cup on their tournament debut.
So, any ideas?
Well, the Best Men's Club are
none other than Manchester City.
Their status as the Premier League's
finest has long been established.
Global success is what
Manchester City crave the most.
Victory over Inter Milan, City landed
the UEFA Champions League
title for the very first time.
A culmination of years of hard work.
Victory over Fluminense,
the final piece of the puzzle was placed.
The city won the FIFA Club World cup,
in the process becoming the first english
club to simultaneously hold
the Premier League, FA Cup,
UEFA Champions League,
UEFA Super Cup and the FIFA Club World
Cup, securing City sporting immortality.
What a season.
What a trophy hall.
Manchester City deservedly
named Best Men's Club.
Going to ask the rest of the team to come
up and join us on stage
with your teammates.
And Kevin, please come on over.
Maybe you could hand off that trophy
to one of your teammates.
Kevin, come and get your
hands on another trophy.
Just here.
Come on in, everyone.
Come on in.
Come on.
Round for the team pic.
Everybody huddle in.
Huddle in.
Let's hear it one for the
Team of the Year.
Manchester City.
So, Kevin, we touched on it a little bit
earlier, but this was the big one,
wasn't it, for Manchester City.
Getting your hands on the
Champions League at last.
What has that meant for you personally?
Well, it's the one that I
missed with this team.
I've been here for nine years and it's
been a lot of heartache
going through the Champions League,
but last year was amazing.
And, yeah, these guys helped me win this
trophy, so I'm very grateful to everybody
for the club, for the guys,
and at least I got one.
And going on,
what are you thinking
in terms of this year?
I mean, it's looking pretty good so
far in terms of repeating the success.
Well, I've seen these
guys play all season.
I've just been sitting on the sidelines
and these guys are amazing.
They did really well in all
the competitions and this
team is ready to go again.
I see the hunger, see the passion,
and let's try again.
Sitting on the sidelines and, if reports
are to be believed, working on your hair.
What's the secret to that?
Just don't go to the barber.
Congratulations.
We look forward to seeing how it grows
and develops, much like the trophy win.
Manchester City.
Congratulations, Manchester City.
And Kevin de Bruyne.
Yeah, congratulations to the entire team
and a huge thanks to all the team
from Manchester City for being
with us here tonight.
So we turn our attention then to the next
of our awards as we come very close
towards the conclusion of proceedings.
Still some big awards to be handed out
from the world champions and continental
champions, and players with trophy
cabinets brimming with accolades.
There's been a steady influx of global
superstars right here in the Middle East.
Add to that a plethora of homegrown talent
and football in the Middle
East is at its most formidable.
That's been evident in some brilliant
performances over the last year.
But who has been the player who delivered
the very best and most consistently?
Yeah, this one's kindly sponsored
by our friends at Italipreziosi.
And the finalists then, are...
Ladies and gentlemen,
the winner of the Dubai Globe Soccer
Awards Best Middle East Player...
I think the roof is about to go off..
Is none other than Cristiano Ronaldo.
It was a magical year for you, Cristiano,
and the accolades just keep on coming.
Your 54 goals in 2023 impressively also
secures you the Maradona Award,
brought to you by Nakheel.
Extraordinarily, this trophy actually
has the exact replica of the late,
great Diego Maradona's foot.
Cristiano Ronaldo further added to his
legacy by taking his talents
to Al-Nassr in Saudi Arabia.
His foresight made the globalization
of football a reality as the eyes of the
world shifted towards the Middle East.
Ronaldo's prowess on the pitch is
undeniable,
but it's his ability for making
revolutionary decisions off
it which sets him apart.
Now, in Riyadh, and spear in the attack
for Al-Nassr, they become the team to beat.
The year 2023 ended with CR7 netting
a staggering and world leading 54 goals.
Both for Al-Nassr and the
Portuguese National team.
Another Globe Soccer Award for Cristiano.
Let's get a few words with them.
Cristiano, congratulations.
Cristiano, we were talking earlier about
how you used the motivation
of some of the criticism.
How important was that first goal
that you scored in Saudi Arabia?
Do you remember?
It was a penalty, I think.
Yes, I remember.
It was a good moment.
It was my first one.
It was good.
It wasn't special because the first
one is always special, but it was good.
I was so proud.
I did amazing season.
I have to say thank you to my teammates,
my coaches from Al-Nassr, from Portugal
national team, and I feel so proud.
I never won this trophy.
The Best Middle East player
and Maradona Award as well.
So I will put
with passion in my museum because it's
two special ones and I'm so proud.
I have to say thank you to my wife,
to my kids that deal with me every day.
Sometimes I know I'm a little bit boring,
but it's my job to be
consistent every time.
So thank you to the Globe Soccer
for this amazing award.
And you have said this is
about more than just you.
This is about growing football
in the game in another region.
How confident are you that the influx
of players will continue?
I hope so.
As I say before
the league, the leagues start
one year ago to grow and grow,
and I'm sure 100% they will continue
to grow because our boss,
they decide and they love football.
And in my opinion, the league will be top.
Top.
Well, top, top.
You've got another trophy to collect.
If I can just usher you back over there.
This is a pretty special,
the Maradona award, complete
with a replica of the foot.
Congratulations.
Yeah, congratulations to Cristiano.
He's going to need all his hands there
for the two trophies as well as
he makes his way off the stage.
Right from one tactical genius to another,
the tactical genius is
the master motivator.
Strategic excellence may be a fundamental
factor, but leadership,
communication and the ability to bring
the best out of any player means
success is almost a certainty.
In 2023, there were coaches,
coaches whose legacies were enhanced.
And we here
at the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards boast
an esteemed list of Best Coach nominees.
Your finalists for the
Best Coach of the Year are...
The best coach of the year at the
Globe Soccer Awards is Pep Guardiola.
With fundamentals surrounding possession,
pressing creativity,
Pep Guardiola has been at the forefront
of the beautiful game's evolution.
Having stamped his authority in Barcelona
and Munich, Guardiola's status was
further elevated at Manchester City.
After dominating the Premier League,
he secured european,
then global success in 2023,
the Champions League in June,
followed by the Club World Cup triumph.
This is a coach who has an obsessive eye
for detail, with the ability to get
the very best out of every
player he's worked with.
2023 is a special year for a
Special Coach.
Congratulations.
I'll just bring you back this little bit.
Firstly, happy birthday.
Not a bad birthday celebration,
getting your hands on another trophy.
But what does it feel like
being the best in the world?
Because we won.
If we don't win, we are not even invited.
So that is the truth.
So to win, there are many, many reasons.
So especially all of them
are sitting there.
And of course, we are here in UAE,
where Abu Dhabi held unconditionally.
Yeah, really, really happy.
How much do you allow yourself
to celebrate the successes?
A lot.
But it's on to next as quick as possible.
But of course we celebrate it.
And especially when the days come through,
the years come through, you'll remember
there will be no forgotten for all of us.
That's for sure.
And have you managed to come
up with an answer yet?
Which is the best?
Your Barcelona team or this one?
It's like as mom and dad to choose.
Both are special.
Which is which?
I'm a daddy's girl.
Personally.
Sorry.
I'm a daddy's girl.
Which is which?
No?
Okay.
Congratulations.
Go join the team.
Congratulations to Pep.
Well done to all
the Man City team yet again.
Okay, next up, we go back
to our career awards.
Our next career award is generously
sponsored by Audi Al Nabooda Automobiles.
A big thanks to all the team there.
And it goes to a player who really does
epitomize inspiration, drive and that all
important, 'never say die' attitude.
We honor the career,
ladies and gentlemen, of Casemiro.
With speed, strength and power,
Casemiro is one of the world's
leading central defensive midfielders.
At club or international level.
Casemiro has a defined role and he's
a player whose physical attributes combine
seamlessly with guile and goal scoring.
A player who thrives in the big moments.
Casemiro has won an astonishing 25
trophies through his illustrious career
of São Paulo, Real Madrid
and now Manchester United.
Congratulations.
I know you'd like to say
a few words in Portuguese.
So, good evening.
I will speak Portuguese.
It's better for me.
Thank you very much to everyone.
It's a pleasure, thank you very much to
Dubai, Globe Soccer
for this great event.
Without a doubt, for me is
a pleasure to receive
an award like this,
a great achievement in my career.
I would like to thank my past clubs
São Paulo, FC Porto, Real Madrid Castilla, Real Madrid,
and after Porto, Manchester United
Without doubt, without them,
I wouldn't be able to win the titles I won.
I wouldn't be able to win in my life,
and without doubt, I wouldn't be the person I am today.
Thank you to my wife,
Anna Mariana,
always with me in the
best and worst moments.
But always with me.
Once again,
Thank you all.
Congratulations.
Enjoy the moment.
I'm feeling slightly under pressure
with the translation,
with so many portuguese speakers
in the room, but Casemiro said
he's grateful for the recognition.
Thanks to all the clubs he's represented
and dedicated the award to his wife Anna,
who has been there throughout
and is with us this evening.
He also said he's only 31 years old
and planning to win a whole lot more.
Wouldn't doubt against it,
that's for sure.
Okay, into the final few of the evening.
Hope you've enjoyed the evening again down
here at the Dubai Globe Soccer
Awards, live from Dubai.
So, for clubs who have redefined the game
of football, be that on the pitch or
of course, in the boardroom,
the climb towards the pinnacle has been
consistent throughout,
from planning and implementation
to the accomplishment of goals.
None of this would have been possible
without the direction from the club
president, who provides the blueprint as
to how clubs strike that perfect balance
in the quest to become
a global football force.
Over the last year, there have been clubs
who have taken their place in the upper
echelons of the football world and clubs
who have consolidated their positions as
global leaders all through the vision
and efforts of the president.
Into your finalists then, for the best
president at the Nakheel Globe Soccer Awards.
And the finalists are...
The winner of the Dubai Globe Soccer Awards
Best President
is Khaldoon al Mubarak of Manchester City.
City's five trophies is
a testament to their growth.
Under the leadership of Khaldoon al Mubarak,
Manchester City have embarked on a journey
that has seen them
conquer all before them.
With their president providing
the blueprint, City's seismic influence
on the beautiful game
shows no sign of abating.
Yeah, on the pitch, they continue
to reach new heights off it.
They've just been a successful club,
posting a Premier League record revenue
for the 22 to 23 financial year.
With the City football group expanding its
network to all corners of the globe,
a lasting legacy has been created.
A 15 year journey and now City are
at the summit of world football.
Khaldoon, maybe we can get
a few words with you.
So many congratulations.
We're talking about an era of dominance,
but sport has eras and peaks and droughts.
So the question is, how long can
Manchester City keep this going?
Well, allow me first to thank
His Highness Sheikh Mansour Bin Mohammed
and Mattar Al Tayer
and of course,
all the organizers for obviously this
privilege to win this award.
And, you know, I accept the award...
But to be honest, my job is not that hard.
When you have...
We just gave you the big sell.
When you have the best players
in the world, when you have the best
coaching staff in the world, when you have
the best organization
in the world, when you have the best
football director, in Txiki Begiristain,
in the world when you have the best CEO,
Ferran Soriano, in the world
and of course, having,
and this is the best of all,
the best owner in his
Highness Sheikh Mansour bin Zayed Al Nahyan
in his unwavering support
and his positivity, always.
And of course,
all of this has to compensate
for a manager that's, I don't know,
a bit average and of course the best
manager in the world in Pep Guardiola.
And let's not forget what makes
Manchester City really special.
We have the best fans in the world.
So with all of this,
my job is pretty easy.
How long can you keep him?
Pep?
Listen, I didn't answer you the first
question, so let me just go back to that.
How do you keep winning?
You keep winning with
a commitment for excellence.
When you wake up every day
with that hunger, with that urge and when
it's consistent in the DNA and the culture
of the club, one of the things I would say
I am most proud of is over this 15 year
journey, what you have today
in Manchester City is a DNA,
a culture that is in every person
that's involved in the club.
And because of that,
when you win 7 Premier leagues
in the last eleven years, when you win
three Premier Leagues in a row,
the first team since 1991, 1999,
to win a triple, the only other
team to win a triple in England.
And this year, obviously we're going to go
for hopefully the fourth Premier League
in a row and maybe another triple,
but that hunger, that urge to get better,
to win, to constantly want to improve,
never to be comfortable,
never to be content,
this is, I think, what makes this
team and this organization special.
This is what makes the 15 years,
I think, a privilege.
But this is why I think you see
a consistency and this is why,
when you look at the future,
I think from our perspective we're always
looking at how to get better,
how to win more and how to constantly
improve and that's going to be
how we build this legacy.
Thank you.
Since we forgot the question.
We can pass it.
Ah, I love it.
Great to speak to you.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, congratulations indeed to Khaldoon.
Doing great to see you, as always.
And well done yet again to all
the team behind Manchester City.
Okay, on to the final awards
of the evening as we gear up to our
climate, the conclusion of the evening
next award has been generously
sponsored by our friends at Nakheel.
Every single professional athlete was...
Well, they started out as a dreamer.
Recognition from their most loyal fans as
what the best in the business strive for.
And there is no greater satisfaction
for any footballer here or out there than
bringing smiles to the faces of fans.
Fans from around the world,
quite literally,
have cast their vote in the hope of seeing
their favorite footballer being crowned
the Fans' Favourite Player of the Year
Let's look into the finalists then.
And the finalists are...
The Fans' Favourite Player of the year,
with an incredible
5 million votes, is Cristiano Ronaldo.
Cristiano Ronaldo continued to underline
his status as one of the world's premier
athletes, winning the most Globe Soccer Awards
since 2010, a testament
to his extraordinary talents.
Historic move to Al-Nassr marks his
significant step in the evolution
of Middle Eastern football and his
continued excellence on the field of play,
his tribute to his unwavering
dedication to his craft.
Ronaldo has a unique ability to captivate
fans across the globe, drawing boasts
from every corner of the world.
It's no surprise he's once again cemented
his status as the fans' favorite.
Would you like to say a final few words?
She asks very difficult questions.
So, as you know,
for me, the most important thing
in football, it's to make the fans happy,
because it's the people who go to the
stadiums to see goals, to see good games.
And if they vote, it's because
they have passion for football.
For me, it's a special award because most
of the times we don't speak about
the fans, but the stadiums without
the fans, if we go back two,
three years ago, to the COVID, when we played
with the empty stadiums, it's no good.
The people, if you ask the players,
they don't enjoy, because, as I say,
without you guys, the football is nothing.
So, thank you very much to voting on me
and keep support the football and keep
support Al-Nassr and Cristiano.
Congratulations, Cristiano Ronaldo,
ladies and gentlemen.
And so, my friends, it comes
down to this, the grand finale.
The final whistle is
just round the corner.
Big thanks to all of you
for your patience.
Big thanks to all the millions
that have tuned in around the world.
So how do you round things off?
Well, from the sublime to the magical
and all the way to the downright
astonishing, superstars from around
the football world have really raised
the standards the football loving
public were constantly glued to
extraordinary action throughout the year.
Defensive resilience, midfield
mastery goal scoring supremacy.
It was a year which will
live long in the memory.
Expectedly, some stars shone brighter
and more consistently
delivered the spectacular.
So it is time to crown
the best of the best.
Your nominees are...
It is quite the list, is it not?
But one of those names has been crowned
the final winner of the evening.
Behind this direction, please, ladies,
gentlemen, honored guests,
Best Men's Player of the Year
of this year's Nakheel
Dubai Globe Soccer Awards goes to...
Erling Haaland.
With a combination of power,
pace and intricate movement,
Erling Haaland has scored against
some of the world's best defenses.
With the tutelage of Pep Guardiola,
Haaland scored a Premier League
record of 36 goals
at 35 league appearances
in his debut season.
Also finishes as the top scorer in Sydney's
triumphant run for the Champions League Glory with 12 goals.
This once in a generation goalscorer is
seamlessly fitted into a team
stacked with creative talents.
His 50 goals in 2023 helps City
win five trophies in the year.
So, the final award of the evening,
the crowning glory.
The Best Men's Player of the Year at this
year's Dubai Globe Soccer Awards
brought to you by
Nakheel, Erling Haaland.
Congratulations.
Just a couple of words, if I may.
It's almost easy to forget at times that
it was only last season you joined City.
What is it about this club squad,
this team that has made it so easy
for you to settle in and shine?
Well, I think, first of all, the people,
the guys that sit here is
a bunch of amazing people.
And then you have the manager,
of course, who is not so bad as well.
So, yeah, it's a fantastic club
and the support we players get
from the administration and everything
and the leaders in the club
is massive as well.
So it's a nice club and I
really enjoy being there.
Not a bad job at all.
Have you still got the Champions League
as your ringtone on your phone?
Now you've won it and done it?
Yeah, I do.
And I love this competition
and, yeah, it was a big dream
when we won it and a fantastic feeling.
Do you know when we're
going to see you back?
I hope really soon because I'm getting
a bit sick of not playing,
so hopefully soon.
Great.
We wish you well with your recovery.
Congratulations once again,
ladies and gentlemen.
Erling...
Oh, oh, hang on a minute,
I got a bit carried away.
Before we let you go, we've got some
special messages from some of your fans.
Just have a look.
Congratulations, Haaland.
Congrats, Haaland.
Congratulations.
"And Erling Haaland..."
Congratulations, Haaland.
Congratulations.
Amazing.
What does that mean when you see that?
Of course, it's amazing.
And what I also want to show
with my career is that no matter where you
come from, I come from
a small town in Norway.
You can come far.
And, yeah, it's about hard work.
It's about having the right
people around you.
And, yeah, it's really beautiful to see.
Amazing.
Congratulations once more,
ladies and gentlemen, Erling Haaland.
Erling.
Congratulations to you.
Erling, we're going to ask you to stay
with us here on stage
as we round things up.
Grab that trophy.
Amanda, what an evening it has been.
Another glorious evening right
here in the heart of Dubai.
The magical setting of the Atlantis The Palm,
where some of the world's
finest talents were honored.
Yeah.
The 14th edition of the Globe Soccer Awards
has delivered a spectacle we'd like
to call upon all of our winners to join,
hurling up on stage to capture what
has been a truly magical evening.
Yeah.
We would like you all now to sit back,
appreciate and applaud
the star performers of 2023.
A huge congratulations for the simply
incredible Cristiano Ronaldo.
Please come and join us.
We're also
going to welcome back onto stage
the entire Manchester City
team, staff, all the winners.
So, come on on, Man City,
let's get you back up.
Including their coach, Coach of the Year,
Pep Guardiola.
Going to ask our Career Award
winners as well, of course.
John Terry, can I ask you
to come and join us up here?
We've got Lionel Scaloni with us as well.
Lionel, I ask you to join us.
And the brazilian Manchester United,
Casemiro. Could ask you,
please, to join us.
We would like to thank
His Highness Sheikh Mansoor bin Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum,
Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council,
and His Excellency Mattar al Tayer,
Vice Chairman of the Dubai Sports Council,
for gracing us with their presence.
We're calling on all of our winners here
tonight to join us up here on the stage.
And a big thank you to each and every one
of them taking their time out
of their busy schedules to be with us.
Jorge, get up here.
Come and join the party as well.
As we say, a big thank you to all of our
partners, all of our sponsors, and,
of course, each and every one of you.
Amanda, bless you.
Thank you.
It's been a great pleasure
to all those tuning in.
Thank you.
We hope to see you here in Dubai next year
and maybe in Sardinia
a little later on this year.
From all the teams at Globe Soccer,
specifically the
Dubai Globe Soccer Awards.
From all of us here in Dubai, it is:
Good Night.